

RODRIGO MATAGAWA

Software Engineer

Details

Address

Brazil, São Paulo - SP 03444-000

Email

rodrigo.matagawa@gmail.com

Nationality

Brazilian

Languages

Portuguese (Native speaker)

English (Proficient)

Links

Portfolio

LinkedIn

GitHub

Profile

Experienced Node.js developer with 5+ years, AWS Lambda expertise, NoSQL/SQL proficiency, and strong CI/CD and RESTful API skills. Passionate problem-solver, embracing challenges for continuous growth.

 $Skills: JavaScript \cdot TypeScript \cdot Node.js \cdot Serverless \cdot AWS \ Lambda, SQS, DynamoDB, \\ CloudWatch \cdot Express.js \cdot Jest \cdot MongoDB \cdot Redis \cdot SQL \ Server \cdot Git \cdot Code \ Review \cdot ESLint \cdot Prettier \cdot CI/CD$

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Code7

Mar 2020 − Present Santa Catarina, Brazil · Remote

- Transformed legacy solution to Node.js using Serverless & AWS Lambda
- Integrated third-party APIs for enhanced functionality
- Developed a proactive chatbot for real-time monitoring of messaging services
- Created a solution responsible for sending over 1 million messages without bottlenecks
- Recreating stored procedures for better reporting performance
- Integration with metrics service (Elastic Kibana) in existing services

Systems Development Analyst JR, Flex Contact

Mar 2019 – Feb 2020 São Paulo, Brazil · Hybrid

- Developed and maintained billing, sales, and FAQ chatbots
- Integrated and trained AI for advanced chatbot understanding
- Implemented chatbot logs for efficient bug tracking and debugging
- Improved Power BI reports for optimized analytical and synthetic visualization

Internship & Support Analyst JR, TQS (Total Quality Systems)

Feb 2017 — Feb 2019

São Paulo, Brazil · On-site

- Mainframe script automation to make the solution easier to use on
- Adjusted functions inside CRM to make the tool better
- Worked with the chatbot development team to improve the performance for a better understanding of the chatbot
- Tested products such as CRM & Chatbots to delivery to customer with homologated status
- Helping the team with problem solving by analyzing the logs
- Giving support to users using our CRM
- Creating manuals and handbooks for team members to help daily tasks

Education

FMU (Faculdades Metropolitanas Unidas), Bachelor of Computer Science

Courses

JS + React + Next + Tests, curso.dev

Jan 2024 - Present

Javascript Expert, ew.it

Jul 2022 — Dec 2023

Ignite - Node.js, Rocketseat

Jan 2021 — Jun 2022

Computer Graphics, FMU (Faculdades Metropolitanas Unidas)

Jun 2014 — Dec 2015

Web Design, CENLEP Educação Profissional

Jan 2013 — Dec 2013